<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deon Taljaard</title>
    <description>I'm Deon Taljaard. An application developer from Centurion, South Africa.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 18:34:09 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 18:34:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first official post and I’ll keep it short (and sweet), so I thought I’d share my experience on how I got up and running with GitHub Pages and Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been looking to create a personal site for myself for a while now. I have finally decided to stop looking and just dive into it. I settled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-github-pages-and-jekyll&quot;&gt;Why GitHub Pages and Jekyll?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, I like to keep things simple. GitHub Pages is hosted directly from your GitHub repo and you can get blogging with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; in no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-theme&quot;&gt;This theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme was created by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bencentra&quot;&gt;Ben Centra&lt;/a&gt; - thanks Ben! You can check it out on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde&quot;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, getting your GitHub repo for your GitHub Pages site was straightforward - the GitHub Pages home page shows you how to get started. Lastly, I had to get my local machine ready for creating and testing my Jekyll site. I run Ubuntu 14.04 LTS, so getting set up wasn’t as simple as double clicking on an installer. Fortunately, I found this helpful &lt;a href=&quot;http://michaelchelen.net/81fa/install-jekyll-2-ubuntu-14-04/&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt;. This guide is very well assembled and the only constraint on how quickly Jekyll will be serving sites on your local machine is your Internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll 3.x requires Ruby version &amp;gt;= 2.0.0, which slightly changes the prerequisites as described in the above mentioned guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two steps to take instead are as follows and were taken from &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/33503796/error-installing-jekyll-requires-ruby-2-0-0&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; SO post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Install Ruby 2.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install ruby2.0 ruby2.0-dev&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. Remove and add symlinks to the new Ruby and Gem binaries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;sudo rm /usr/bin/ruby
sudo rm /usr/bin/gem
sudo ln -s /usr/bin/ruby2.0 /usr/bin/ruby
sudo ln -s /usr/bin/gem2.0 /usr/bin/gemv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The step below is only applicable for if you’re using the Centrarium theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After cloning the Centrarium template (there is an installation guide) and serving it on Jekyll, the only ‘error’ message I saw was the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
Deprecation: You appear to have pagination turned on, but you haven't included the `jekyll-paginate` gem. Ensure you have `gems: [jekyll-paginate]` in your configuration file.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The message describes how to resolve it, so it was easy to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started with Jekyll was remarkably simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, using GitHub Pages and Jekyll has been a pleasant experience. I look forward to learn more about Jekyll. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://michaelchelen.net/81fa/install-jekyll-2-ubuntu-14-04/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/33503796/error-installing-jekyll-requires-ruby-2-0-0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/19/hello-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/03/19/hello-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
